Guide to the Women Hospital Workers Oral History Collection OH.006
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Women Hospital Workers Oral History Collection
1979
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sexton, Patricia Cayo
OH.006
2 Linear Feet in 1 letter manuscript box, 1 half letter manuscript box, and 2 flat boxes.
67 audiocassettes
This collection contains interviews of hospital workers conducted in 1979, including both recorded interviews on audiocassettes and interview transcripts. The interviewees are primarily women, with a few men represented as well. They are members of SEIU Locals across the United States, and include nurses, nursing attendants, lab supervisors, researchers, therapists, food service workers, custodians, business agents, secretaries, and more. They discuss topics such as experiences of sexism and racism on the job, working conditions, union organizing, the women's movement, maternity leave, pay inequities, and workplace hierarchies. The collection includes both recorded interviews on audiocassettes and interview transcripts.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Patricia Cayo Sexton in circa 1979. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.129.
Historical Note
Healthcare workers first joined Service Employees International Union (SEIU) in 1941, when workers in San Francisco organized their hospital and won their first contract. Interview participants represented in this collection come from SEIU Locals across the United States.
Many of the interviews reference George Hardy's leadership as President from 1971-1980. During his tenure, the union saw rapid growth and organized its first local union of physicians. Merges and affiliations accounted for much of the growth during this time. There is also much discussion of the 1966 hospital workers strike in Los Angeles, which led to the Meyers-Milias-Brown Act, the first public employee law on collective bargaining in California.
In addition to union organizing, history and structure, the interview participants discuss at length their thoughts on the women's rights movement and experiences of sexism and racism at work. Major themes include paid maternity leave, discrimination faced by pregnant women, pay inequity, and workplace sexual harrassment. The participants also discuss their relationship with the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), a national organization that formed in 1974 to advocate for women's issues within the labor movement.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains interviews of hospital workers conducted in 1979, including both recorded interviews on audiocassettes and interview transcripts. The interviewees are primarily women, with a few men represented as well. The creator of this collection and conductor of the interviews are unknown. In some interviews with women participants, the first name of the interviewee is omitted from source materials and therefore unknown.
The interviewees are members of SEIU Locals across the United States, and include nurses, nursing attendants, lab supervisors, researchers, therapists, food service workers, custodians, business agents, secretaries, and more. They discuss topics such as experiences of sexism and racism on the job, working conditions, union organizing, the women's movement, maternity leave, pay inequities, and workplace hierarchies. Some interviews include multiple interviewees, and are based on a particular topic such as the women's movement. Not all audio recordings have a transcript, and not all transcripts have an audio counterpart.
Arrangement
Interviews are arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name. Some interviews include multiple participants, and are based on a particular topic such as the women's movement; in these cases, they are arranged alphabetically by the subject of the interview.
Hospitals -- United States -- History.; Strikes and lockouts -- United States.; Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions; Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; Hospitals -- Employees -- Interviews.; Labor unions; Labor unions -- Organizing.; Women's rights -- United States -- 20th century; Women employees.; Women employees -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews.; Women in the labor movement -- United States; Women -- Employment -- United States.; Sexton, Patricia Cayo; Service Employees International Union; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.)
- Allison, Sylvia, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arballo, Bill, September 4, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_001, Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ball, Dolores, September 10, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_002, Box 1, Folder 3)
- Beasley, Cora, August 23, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_003, Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bierer, Charlene, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bisher, Sondra, June 22, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_004, 006_005, Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bragg, Lily, August 20, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_006, Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brooks, Dovie, August 20, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_007, Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brooks, Mae, September 6, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_008, Box 1, Folder 9)
- Broussard, Bobbie, August 23, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_009, Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brumfield, Anna, June 15, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_010, 006_011, Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bryant, Ollie, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Butterfield, Sandy, September 18, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_012, Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cabell, Connie, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Caton, Vivian, September 12, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_013, Box 1, Folder 15)
- Collins, Mary Ann, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Daniels, Ophelia, August 28, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_013, Box 1, Folder 17)
- Dixon, Mae, September 5, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_014, Box 1, Folder 18)
- Douglas, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Scope and Contents
  The participant's name is listed as "Mrs. Douglas" with her first name omitted.
- Dowden, Hellan, September 17, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_015, 006_016, Box 1, Folder 20)
- Drozd, Paul, circa 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_017, Box 1, Folder 21)
- Dumbauld, Deborah, July 17, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_018, Box 1, Folder 22)
- Edwards, Audrey, August 17, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_019, Box 1, Folder 23)
- Edwards, Patsy, August 22, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_020, Box 1, Folder 24)
- Estrada, David, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Faniel, Diana, September 10, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_002, 006_021, Box 1, Folder 26)
- Filapowski, June, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Floyd, Robin, September 10, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_022, Box 1, Folder 28)
- Gallelos, Esperanza, September 5, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_023, Box 1, Folder 29)
- Gantt, September 7, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_024, Box 1, Folder 30)
  The participant's name is listed as "Mrs. Gantt" with her first name omitted.
- Garcia, Susana, September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_010, 006_025, 006_026, Box 1, Folder 31)
- Geagan, John, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Glenn, Elinor, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Group Interview: Marilyn Mbagwn and Carolyn Riley, September 12, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_051)
- Grystar, Ed, June 14, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_027, Box 1, Folder 34)
- Haer, John, June 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_028, Box 1, Folder 35)
- Hangford, Susie, August 28, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_012)
- Hardy, George, November 28,1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_029, Box 1, Folder 36)
- Hawkins, Rita, September 6, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_030, Box 1, Folder 37)
- Herschberger, Cheryl, June 25, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_031, Box 1, Folder 38)
- Jackson, Lois, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Kassalow, Sylvia, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Keener, Stephanie, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Keffer, Kathy, June 29, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_032, Box 1, Folder 42)
- Kimmel, Phyllis, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Krauss, Al, September 19, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_033, Box 1, Folder 44)
- Kravice, Cecilia, July 6, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_034, Box 1, Folder 45)
- Kronk, Jane, July 10, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_035)
- Kujawa, Elsie, June 26, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_036, Box 1, Folder 46)
- Langford, Susan, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Long, Diane, August 27, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_067, Box 1, Folder 48)
- Lopez, Josephine, August 20, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_026)
- Love, Evelyn, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Luna, Eileen, September 6, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_037, Box 1, Folder 50)
- Luna, Maria, August 27, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_038, Box 1, Folder 51)
- Maricondia, Pat, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Marigny, Gloria, August 23, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_039, Box 1, Folder 53)
- McCone, Helen, September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_030, Box 1, Folder 54)
- McFadden, Ophelia, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Miller, Walter, August 14, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_040, Box 1, Folder 56)
- Mills, Nancy, May 14, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_041, Box 1, Folder 57)
- Murphy, Dick, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Mushenski, Nancy, September 11, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_042, Box 1, Folder 59)
- Nicklow, Rosella, June 29, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_043, Box 1, Folder 60)
- O'Connor, Fotine, circa 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_044, Box 1, Folder 61)
- Oravetz, Pauline, June 28, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_045, Box 1, Folder 62)
- Organizing Women Hospital Workers, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Pearman, Sally, June 22, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_046, Box 1, Folder 64)
- Piper, Carolyn, June 26, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_047, Box 1, Folder 65)
- Polisar, Lisa, November 28, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_029)
- Remson, Ann, September 12, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_041, 006_048, Box 1, Folder 66)
- Reynouard, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  The participant's name is listed as "Mr. Reynouard" with his first name omitted.
- Rice, Marjorie, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Richardson, Ann, September 19, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_022, Box 3, Audiocassette 006_049, Box 1, Folder 69)
- Ridgely, Hattie, June 27, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_050, Box 1, Folder 70)
- Riley, Carolyn, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Rodriguez, Margarita, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Saland, Bonnie, August 22, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_048)
- Santore, Rosemary, June 21, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_052, Box 1, Folder 73)
- Singleton, September 7, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_053, Box 1, Folder 74)
- Smith, Rosina, September 13, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_054, Box 1, Folder 75)
- Smouse, Claudia, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Staszel, Emma, June 21, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_055, Box 1, Folder 77)
- Stirbis, Flo, July 11, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_056, Box 4, Folder 1)
- Stoffel, Leonore, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Taylor, circa 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_057, Box 4, Folder 3)
  The participant's name is listed as "Ms. Taylor" with her first name omitted.
- Thompson, Evelyn, circa 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_058)
- Tissue, Dolores, June 27, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_059, Box 4, Folder 4)
- Troy, Susan, September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_014, Box 3, Audiocassette 006_060, Box 4, Folder 5)
- Trujillo, Alice, September 10, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_063, Box 4, Folder 6)
- Trump, Rose, July 7, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_061, 006_062, Box 4, Folder 7)
- Union Structure and History, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  This interview features Elinor Glenn, John Geagan, June Filapowsky, Dick Murphy, and Stephanie Keener.
- Weinlein, Anthony, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Welsh, Bob, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Welsh, Geagen, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Werry, Rita, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Wiltrout, Virginia, June 21, 1979 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_064, 006_065, 006_066, Box 4, Folder 13)
- Wisniewski, Judith, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Women Hospital Workers Questionaire, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Women's Issues, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Women's Movement, CLUW, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)